Jidnyasa Anil Kolhe

Boston, Massachusetts • (617) 717-9239 • jkolhe@umassd.edu • https://www.linkedin.com/in/jidnyasa-kolhe-a23775170/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Front-End Developer with 2 years of experience in building websites/web applications. Organized deadline-oriented problem solver with strong learning mindset. Able to effectively self-manage during independent project as well as collaborate as part of a team. Looking for an opportunity in front-end/UI/Web Developer/Design Engineer.

EDUCATION

M.S in Computer Science, University of Massachusetts, Dartmouth, MA

B.E in Computer Engineering, University of Mumbai, Mumbai, India

Diploma in Computer Engineering, University of Mumbai, Mumbai, India

May 2016

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Database: MySQL, SQL Server Visualization: Tableau, D3.js, JavaScript

Programming Languages: Python, Java

Web Designing HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, PHP

Other Skills: Project Management, Statistical Analysis, Data Analysis, Public Relation

CERTIFICATION

Web Development Sept 2016
Python Programming Language Feb 2018

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

University of Massachusetts Dartmouth

Sept 2019 - Present

- Contributed to developing a Parking portal by leveraging previous web ticking portal design using JavaScript.
- Developed a Parking allotment visualization dashboard in D3.js to distinguish between Students and Employees.
- Handled UMass Pass Access authentication leveraging Vivo net Enterprise tool.

OneRoof Technologies LLP

Oct 2016 - Jan 2019

OneRoof offers services of entire software, Web Development, Mobile Development, Social Media Marketing, Digital Media Marketing, Content Management Solutions, Creative Design and to carry out web-based projects, e-commerce, mobile applications, web applications

- Designed and developed websites, web pages, web applications for clients using HTML, JavaScript and D3.js.
- Developed UI for investment banking clients by modifying large raw datasets to interactive visual effects leveraging D3js which helped them to analyse investments and track their patterns.
- Spearheaded a team to design and develop web-application to help a start-up company in their Digital Media Marketing utilizing editing tools such as Adobe Premiere Pro which boosted annual revenue by 8%.

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

Netflix Data Visualization

Sept 2020 – Dec 2020

- Designed Visual effects for Netflix to find similar categories and ratings for movie/series using D3.js and HTML.
- Helped my team in analysing which two movies are popular in a country based on their rating by implementing SVGs for the effect.

SQL query evaluator for single-threaded database that can run TPC-H queries

Jan 2020 - May 2020

- Designed and developed an SQL Query Evaluator from scratch.
- Optimized the Query Evaluator to decrease execution speed of the queries by implementing techniques such as selection pushdown and joins algorithms. Utilized: Java, CCJSqlParser, Apache Commons CSV

Multi-Level secured banking transaction using Biometric Scan

Jul 2018 – Apr 2019

- Skilfully developing a prototype for banking transaction using biometric scan (Fingerprint) where the biometrics are linked to an individual's bank.
- Authentication of user's fingerprint was done using Java Language.

Hobby World - Website to connect learners and tutors

June 2017 - Nov 2017

- Efficiently designing a website for all the learners who wish to learn online without any time limit.
- Designing Front-end web application using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap. Back-end connection using PHP.